So let's compare the perceptron algorithm and the gradient descent algorithm.
我们将感知器算法与梯度下降算法进行对比
In the gradient descent algorithm,
在梯度下降算法中
we take the weights and change them from Wi to Wᵢ + α(ŷ - y)xᵢ.
我们将权重从 Wi 更改为 Wᵢ + α(ŷ - y)xᵢ
In the perceptron algorithm not every point changes the weights,
在感知器算法中 并非每个点都会更改权重
only the misclassified ones.
只有分类错误的点才会
Here, if x is misclassified we'll change the weights by
这里当 x 分类错误时 如果点标签是正的
adding xᵢ to wᵢ if the point label is positive and subtracting if it's negative.
我们将 xᵢ 加到 wᵢ 上 如果是负值 则用 wᵢ 减去 xᵢ
Now the question is, are these two things the same?
现在的问题是 二者是一回事吗？
Well, let's remember that in the perceptron algorithm the labels are 1 and 0,
在感知器算法中 标签是 1 和 0
and the predictions ŷ are also 1 and 0.
预测 ŷ 也是 1 和 0
So if the point is correct, classified.
所以如果点分类正确
Then y - ŷ is 0 because y is equal to ŷ.
则 y - ŷ = 0 因为 y 等于 ŷ
Now if the point is labeled blue,
如果点标为蓝色
then y = 1,
则 y = 1
and if it's misclassified then the prediction must be ŷ = 0.
如果分类错误 那么预测必须是 ŷ = 0
So ŷ - y is -1.
所以 ŷ - y 为 -1
Similarly, with points labeled red,
类似地 如果点标为红色
then y = 0 and ŷ = 1.
那么 y = 0 且 ŷ = 1
So ŷ - y = 1.
所以 ŷ - y = 1
This may not be super clear right away but if you stare the screen for long
现在可能还不太清晰 但是如果仔细盯着屏幕看
enough you realize that the right and the left are exactly the same thing.
就会发现左右是完全相同的
The only difference is that in the left,
唯一的区别是 在左侧
ŷ can take any number between 0 and 1,
ŷ 可以是 0 到 1 之间的任何值
whereas in the right,
但是在右侧
ŷ can take only the values 0 or 1.
ŷ 只能是值 0 或 1
It's pretty fascinating, isn't it?
很神奇 对不对？
But let's study gradient descent even more carefully.
我们再仔细研究下梯度下降
Both in the perceptron algorithm and in the gradient descent algorithm,
在感知器算法和梯度下降算法中
a point that has misclassified tells a line to come closer
分类错误的点都会告诉直线靠近点
because eventually it wants the line to surpass it so it can be in the correct side.
因为最终都希望点穿过它 使其位于正确的区域
Now what happens if the point is correctly classified?
如果点分类正确 会怎样呢？
Well, the perceptron algorithm says do absolutely nothing.
感知器算法就会说什么也不要做
In the gradient descent algorithm you are changing the weights but what is it doing.
在梯度算法中 你会更改权重 但是在干什么呢
Well, if we look carefully,
如果仔细观察
what the point is telling the line is to go farther away.
就会发现点是在告诉直线离的更远些
And this makes sense, right?
有道理 对吧？
Because if you are correctly classified,
因为如果分类正确的话
say if you are a blue point in the blue region,
假设是蓝色区域的蓝点
you'd like to be even more into the blue region,
你会希望跑到蓝色区域的更远处
so your prediction is even closer to 1 and your error is even smaller.
这样预测就更接近 1 误差更小
Similarly for a red point in the red region.
类似地 对于红色区域的红点
So it makes sense that the point tells the line to go farther
点告诉直线离的更远些 是合理的
away and that's precisely what the gradient descent algorithm does.
梯度下降算法就是这么做的
The misclassified points ask the line to come closer
分类错误的点要求直线靠近点
and the correctly classified points ask the line to go farther away.
分类正确的点要直线离远点
The line listens to all the points and take steps in
直线聆听所有点的需求
such a way that it eventually arrives to a pretty good solution.
并采取措施 最终获得很好的解决方案